Register to The Armin Loos Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Musical works by Loos, 1918-1971; Series XIV
  - Dated Works, XIV.A
    - [Symphony, string orchestra] Symphony for large string orchestra., 1940-1944 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      - Another version: arr. for piano, 4 hands?, no date; 1 (Box 7, Folder 119)
        Holograph in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (41 p.); 35 cm. Incomplete, first pages wanting?
    - War Suite, for piano, 1941; 4 (Box 7, Folder 120)
      Sketch in pencil. [4] p.; 35 cm. Movements I-II only. Contains some sketches for arrangements for orchestra.
      Holograph signed, in ink. 35 cm.
      I. pp. 1-2 -- no date
      II. pp. 2-4 -- Mar 19
      III. pp. 5-8 -- no date
      IV. pp. 9-11 -- Jul 29-30
      V. pp. 11-14 -- no date
      VI. pp. 13-16 -- Incomplete, last pages wanting?
      Sketch in pencil. [4] p.; 35 cm. Movement VI, Toccata (Russia defeating the German army) -- no date
      Another version: arr. for piano, 4 hands?
      Holograph in ink. 34 cm. Contains some sketches in pencil for orchestration, and measure numbers.
      I. [2] p. -- no date
      [II.] [5] p. -- no date
      III. [6] p. -- no date
      ? [4] p. -- no date
      IV. [5] p. -- 1941 Jul 29
      V. [6] p. -- no date
      VI. (Russia defeating the Nazi hordes) [6] p. The last 2 pages are in pencil. -- no date
    - [Pieces, piano], 1941 Apr 2; 1 (Box 7, Folder 120)
      Holograph, in pencil. [1] leaf.; 33 cm. Unidentifiable sketch on back.
    - [Works, piano], 1941 Apr 4; 1 (Box 7, Folder 120)
      Holograph in pencil. [1] p.; 34 cm. [4] pages of sketches on back include nos. 2 and 4 (Tango)
    - [Works, piano], 1941 Apr 10-11; 1 (Box 7, Folder 120)
      Sketch in pencil. [3] p.; 34 cm. On 1st p.: no. 4, for my wife's success.
    - Pastorale and Perpetuum mobile, for orchestra, 1941; 2 (Box 7, Folder 121-122)
      Holograph signed, in ink. Score (56 p.); 34 cm. Contains some markings in pencil.
      Microfilm of score, roll 2. (in Box 4)
    - [Symphony] Symphony for orchestra (in canon form), 1941; 1 (Box 7, Folder 123)
      Holograph signed, in ink. Score (74 p.); 34 cm. Contains sketches in pencil.
    - In admiration of the Red Army, for piano, 1942; 1 (Box 7, Folder 123)
      Holograph in ink. [1] p.; 32 cm. 3 pages of sketches in pencil on back.
    - For four violins, 1942; 1 (Box 7, Folder 123)
      Sketch in pencil. 8, [5] p.; 35 cm.
    - [Preludes, piano] Five preludes, for piano., 1946; 3 (Box 5, Folder 96)
      - Holograph signed, in ink. 8 p.; 31 cm. Included in notebook with [Works, piano. Selections], 1918-1929. (Box 5, Folder 96)
      - Photocopy of holograph signed. 8 p. 32 cm. (Box 7, Folder 123)
      - Holograph signed, in ink. [2] p.; 34 cm. Nos. I-II, only. (Box 7, Folder 123)
    - Missa Spiritorum, for orchestra., [1948?]; 5 (Box 8, Folder 124)
      - Holograph signed, in ink. Score (77 p.); 34 cm. Includes some corrections in pencil., 1 (Box 8, Folder 124)
        Photocopy of above, roll 2.
      - Sketches in ink and pencil. Includes 4 leaves of onionskin., 1 (Box 8, Folder 125)
      - Another version: Missa Spiritorum, for orchestra and chorus., 1 (Box 12, Folder 159)
        Holograph signed, in pencil with title and signature in ink. Score (72 p.); 87 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings] Missa brevis spiritorum, [1952?]; 5 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      Holograph in ink. Score (8 p.); 34 cm. and parts. 32 cm.
      Photocopy of above. Score. 36 cm.
      Sketches in pencil. 33 cm.
    - Le Dormeur du Val, for voice and piano, 1953; 1 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      Sketch in pencil. Piano-vocal score. ([2] p.); 34 cm. Words in French by Rimbaud.
    - [Works, piano?], 1954 Apr 30; 1 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] p.; 34 cm. On back: sketch for A Thanksgiving, for horn and piano.
    - [Pieces, horn and piano] Three pieces for horn and piano., 1959-1963; 5 (Box 8, Folder 127)
      Another version: Two pieces for horn and piano. -- 1959
      Holograph signed, ink. Score (5 p.); 34 cm. Note in pencil: this version 1? (2nd version or copy 1963) these 2 pieces to become the last 2 pieces in final version? Incomplete, last pages wanting?
      Another version: Three pieces for horn and piano. -- 1963
      Holograph signed, in ink. Score (17 p.); 34 cm. In 2 sections. First piece pp. 1-8, 2nd and 3rd, pp. 9-17, and part. 32 cm.
      Photocopy of score. 32 cm. and part, with corrections in pencil.
    - [Works, piano], 1960 Jul 3; 1 (Box 8, Folder 127)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] p.; 34 cm. 3 pages of sketches in pencil included.
    - [Songs] Three songs., 1962; 6
      - Another version, originally: Two songs for alto and soprano. -- 1962 Mar, 1 (Box 8, Folder 127)
        Holograph in ink, with English translation in pencil. Piano-vocal score (6 p.); 32 cm. I. Soupir (Sully Prudhomme), words in French. II. Lebewohl (Heinrich Heine), words in German. "Soupir" is not included in Three songs.
      - Another version: Three songs, for alto and piano., 1 (Box 8, Folder 127)
        Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Piano-vocal score (13 p.); 31 cm.
        I. The Triumph (Ben Johnson.) II. Lebewohl. III. Oh Fair, Oh Sweet (Sir Philip Sidney 1554-1586)
        Photocopy of above. 32 cm.
      - The Triumph, [1962]; 1 (Box 8, Folder 127)
        Holograph in ink with corrections in pencil. Piano-vocal score (6 p.); 32 cm. Incomplete, pages 3-4 wanting.
        2 Sketches in ink and pencil. Piano-vocal scores (4, [2] p.); 32 cm.
    - [Songs], 1962 Apr 1; 1 (Box 8, Folder 127)
      Sketch in pencil. piano-vocal score ([4] p.); 34 cm.
    - [Quartet, string, no. 4] String quartet no. 4, 1962-1963; 4 (Box 8, Folder 128)
      - Holograph signed, in ink with corrections and bowings in pencil. Score (23 p.); 35 cm., 1 (Box 8, Folder 128)
      - Holograph signed, in ink. Score (17 p.); 34 cm. 2nd version and parts., 1 (Box 8, Folder 128)
      - Another version: String quartet no. 4; arr. for piano, 1964 Mar 18; 10 (Box 8, Folder 129)
        Holograph in ink. 25 p.; 32 cm. Note in pencil on title page: to facilitate score reading only.
      - Another version: String quartet no. 4., 1 (Box 8, Folder 129)
        Holograph signed, in ink. Score (22 p.); 35 cm. and parts. 32 cm. -- 1965
      - Published copy (1965) [Hillsdale, N.Y.]: Mobart Music Publications [c1979] miniature score (32 p.); 23 cm. -- 1979, 1 (Box 8, Folder 129)
      - Holograph signed, in ink. Score (22 p.); 35 cm. Different version. -- no date, 1 (Box 8, Folder 129)
        Photocopy of above. 28 cm. In poor condition.
        Violin part to above. Holograph signed, in ink. 13 p.; 32 cm.
        Holograph in ink. Score (16 p.); 34 cm. Incomplete, last movement wanting. [2] p. of sketches in pencil at end. -- no date
        Holograph in ink. Score (pp. 9-16 only); 35 cm. Incomplete, pages wanting?
        Sketches signed, in ink and pencil. Score ([6] p.); 35 cm.
    - Psalm 120, for chorus (SATTB) and orchestra., 1963 Oct 15; 6 (Box 9, Folder 130)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (32 p.); 34 cm.
      Photocopy of above. 36 cm.
      Another version: Psalm 120, for chorus (SMzATB) unacc., or 3 violas and 2 violoncelli: Psalm 120 à 5 voci (a capella)
      Holograph signed, in ink. Score (6 p.); 34 cm.
      Photocopy of above. 28 cm.
      Another version: Psalm 120 à voci, for piano or organ.
      Holograph in ink. 4 p. 32 cm.
      Another version: Psalm 120.
      Sketches in ink and pencil. 32, 34 cm.
    - [Sonata, piano, no. 1], 1964 Jun; 2 (Box 9, Folder 131)
      Piano sonata no. 1
      Holograph signed, in ink. 16 p.; 31 cm.
    - [Quartet, oboe, horn, bassoon, and piano], 1964; 3 (Box 9, Folder 132)
      Quartet for wind instruments and piano in classical style.
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (35p.); 34 cm. and parts. 32 cm.
    - [Quintet, woodwind] Woodwind quintet., 1963; 3 (Box 9, Folder 133)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (18 p.); 34 cm. and part 32 cm.
      Holograph signed, in ink. Score (15 p.); 35 cm. Different version.
    - Processional for Iris; arr. for piano, 1965 Jul 28; 1 (Box 9, Folder 134)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. 4 p.; 31 cm.
    - [Concerto, violin], 1965; 1 (Box 9, Folder 134)
      Violin concerto.
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([11] p.); 34 cm. Sketch in pencil of Sonata III on back.
    - [Sonata, piano, no. 2], 1966; 6 (Box 9, Folder 134)
      Klavier Sonate II
      Sketch in pencil. [2] p.; 34 cm. -- 1966 Jun 12
      Holograph signed, in ink. 15 p.; 31 cm. -- 1966 Sep
      Note on front cover: replaced by version no. 2.
      Holograph in ink with corrections in pencil. 15 p.; 31 cm. Sketch in pencil of Study piece for horn, 'cello, and piano (1963) on back. Note on front cover: old version. 1st version? See also Klavier Sonate II also replaced by version no. 2. -- 1966
      Holograph signed, in ink with pedal markings in pencil. 19 p.; 31 cm. 2nd version. -- 1966
      Photocopy of holograph, with corrections in pencil. 20 p.; 31 cm. Note on 1st page: not to be played. See: Folder 135, notebook containing Piano sonata no. 3 and Vier Klavierstücke (1967.) -- no date
      Sketch in pencil. [2] p.; 34 cm. -- no date
    - [Pieces, piano] Vier Klavierstücke., 1967; 2 (Box 9, Folder 135)
      Another version, originally: Suite, for piano.
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. 18 p.; 31 cm.
      I. Petite berceuse -- 1967 Jun 24
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. 19 p.; 31 cm. -- 1967
    - [Sonata, piano, no. 3] Klavier Sonate III., 1967; 5 (Box 9, Folder 135)
      Another version, originally: Fantasia, for piano.
      Holograph in ink, with corrections in pencil. 12 p.; 31 cm. Sketches in pencil at end.
      Another version: Fantasie.
      Sketches signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. 31 cm.
      Another version: Klavier Sonate III.
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. 17 p.; 31 cm. See: notebook containing [Pieces, piano], 1967.
    - [Works, orchestra], 1967; 1 (Box 9, Folder 135)
      Sketch in pencil. 34 cm.
    - [Sonata, violin] Violin Sonate., 1968; 6 (Box 9, Folder 136)
      Violin part. Holograph in ink. 11 p.; 32 cm. Note on 1st p.: 1st version replaced by 2nd version.
      Holograph signed, in ink with measure numbers in pencil. Score (40 p.); 31 cm. and part. 32 cm.
      Photocopy of score. 32 cm.
      2 Sketches in pencil. 31 cm.
    - Piece, unspecified medium, 1969 May 29; 1 (Box 10, Folder 137)
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([3] p.); 34 cm. Unidentified sketch on back.
    - Percepts, for chamber orchestra, 1969; 4
      - Holograph signed, in ink. Score (22 p.); 34 cm. and parts. 32 cm. (Box 10, Folder 137)
      - Photocopy of score. 34 cm. (Box 10, Folder 138)
      - 2 Sketches in ink and pencil of score and B-flat clarinet part. 34, 32 cm. (Box 10, Folder 138)
    - Study for 2 'cellos, 1969; 2 (Box 10, Folder 138)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (7 p.); 32 cm. Sketch in pencil of String quartet on back.
      Sketch in ink with corrections in pencil. 32 cm.
    - Study piece, for violoncello and piano, 1969; 3 (Box 10, Folder 139)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections and measure numbers in pencil. Score (7 p.); 31 cm. and part. 32 cm.
      Sketch in ink and pencil. 31 cm.
    - Study piece II-III, for violoncello and piano, 1969; 3 (Box 10, Folder 139)
      Holograph signed, in ink. Score (9 p.); 32 cm.
      I. pp. 1-4
      II. pp. 5-9
      Another version: Study piece II: Cantilena.
      Holograph in ink with corrections in pencil. Score ([4] p.); 31 cm. Note on 1st page: revised as study piece II.
    - Study piece for horn, 'cello, and piano, 1969; 1 (Box 10, Folder 139)
      Holograph signed, in ink. Score (6 p.); 32 cm. Contains performance markings.
    - Aquarius 70, for string orchestra, 1970; 1 (Box 10, Folder 140)
      - Holograph signed, in ink. Score. 34 cm., 1 (Box 10, Folder 140)
        1. (7 p.) -- 1970 Jan 22-31
        II. (7 p.) -- 1970 Feb 3-6
        III. (8 p.) and parts. 32 cm. -- 1970 Mar 1-9
      - Sketches signed, in ink and pencil., 3 (Box 10, Folder 141)
        I. 2 copies. On last page of last one: revised. 34 cm. -- 1970 Jun 22-31
        II. 34 cm. and part to violin II. 32 cm. -- no date
      - Another version: arr. for piano., 1 (Box 10, Folder 141)
        Holograph signed, in ink with corrections and measure markings in pencil. 12 p.; 31 cm. Sketch in pencil on back. -- [1970?]
    - Pisces 70, [orchestra?], [1970?]; 1 (Box 10, Folder 141)
      Sketch in pencil. 31 cm.
    - [Sonata, violin, no. 2] Sonata II, violin a piano., 1970-1971; 3 (Box 10, Folder 142)
      Violin part. Holograph signed. 12 leaves; 28 cm. Note on 1st page: pasted xerox copy of original darkened by Jerry Laszloffy.
      movement I -- no date
      movement II -- 1970
      movement III -- 1971 Mar
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (28 p.); 31 cm.
      Photocopies of score and part. 28 cm.
  - Undated works, XIV.B
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Bah, Bah Blacksheep, for piano., 2 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Sketch in pencil. [4] p.; 32 cm.
      Sketch in ink on back.
      Sketches in ink and pencil. [9] p.; 35 cm.
    - Canon e antiphonia: Prayer II, [for chorus (SATB), and piano?], 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Sketch in pencil. [8] p.; 35 cm.
    - La Chasse, for piano., 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] p.; 34 cm. Unidentified song in German on back.
    - [Divertimento, orchestra] Divertimento für orchester; arr. for piano., 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Sketch signed, in ink. [1] p.; 35 cm. Sketch for Fünf Klavierstücke on back.
    - [Divertimento, piccolo, flute, and 2 clarinets] Divertimento for flutes and clarinets., 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Sketch in pencil. [3] p.; 34 cm. Unidentified sketch of orchestral piece on back.
    - Elegia, for piano., 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Holograph, in pencil. [3] p.; 35 cm. Unidentified sketch on back.
    - For my wife (II), for piano., 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] leaf; 35 cm.
    - Gesang am Nachmittag, 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Sketch in pencil. Piano-vocal score ([2] p.); 34 cm.
    - In my distress I called upon the Lord, [string orchestra?], 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
    - Kyrie, for chorus (SMzATB) unacc., 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Holograph, in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (6 p.); 45 cm. On back there is a sketch of unidentified choral work, words in English.
    - Kyrie and Et in spiritum sanctum, for piano., 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Sketch in pencil. [3] p.; 34 cm.
    - Lento, for orchestra., 4 (Box 10, Folder 144)
      - Another version, originally: Prelude to Easter: Prelude for full orchestra., 1 (Box 10, Folder 144)
        Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (33 p.); 34 cm. and parts. 35 cm. Incomplete, oboe, English horn, trombone, tuba, percussion I, violin II, viola and violoncello parts wanting.
      - Parts., 1 (Box 10, Folder 144)
        Holographs in ink. 34 cm. Onion skin. Violin II, viola, violoncello, and double bass parts only.
      - Another version: arr. for piano, 4 hands., 1 (Box 10, Folder 144)
        Holograph in ink. Score (14 p.); 35 cm.
      - Another version: Lento, for orchestra., 2 (Box 10, Folder 145)
        Holograph in ink. Score (31 p.); p. 1 is 37 cm.; 38 cm. Onionskin.
        2 Photocopies of above. 36, 40 cm. Larger one is housed in Folder 12/160.
    - March, for piano., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. [2] p.; 35 cm.
    - [Mass, chorus of 6 voices] Missa in signo terroris à 6 voci., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([1] p.); 35 cm.
    - Musica ? sopra un thema continuo (quasi passacaglia), for piano., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in ink. [2] p.; 34 cm.
    - Music for orchestra II., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] leaf.; 34 cm.
    - Music for strings., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([5] p.); 34 cm.
    - Music for 2 pianos., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([2] p.); 35 cm.
    - Musica per orchestra., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. Condensed score (1 p.); 16 cm. Torn in half.
    - My light thou art, for chorus of 5 voices., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([5] p.); 35 cm.
    - Mysterium?, for orchestra., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. Score (2 p.); 35 cm.
    - [Overture, piano?] Vorspiel., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in ink. [1] leaf.; 34 cm. Sketch of Preludio, for piano? on back.
    - [Overture] Vorspiel., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in ink. Condensed score ([4] p.); 34 cm.
    - Peregrina., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Holograph in pencil. Piano-vocal score ([1] p.); 34 cm. Words in German by Mörike. Unidentified sketch on back.
    - Pezzo magico (Alla memoria de Ferruccio Busoni), [for orchestra?], 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. Condensed score ([2] p.); 33 cm.
    - Pezzo pastorale, [piano?], 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. 17 cm. Unidentified sketch on back, only one half of the page remains.
    - [Pieces, piano] Fünf Klavierstücke., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Holograph in ink. [3] p.; 34 cm. Incomplete, 1st piece and sketch of Prologue only.
    - [Pieces, piano] Pieces for the young (canon in memory of Orlando Lassus)., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. [2] p.; 35 cm. Unidentified sketch on back.
    - Prayer for the return of my ticket and that the rug should be in the house, unspecified medium., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Holograph in pencil. [5] p.; 35 cm. At end of piece: to Mr. R. P-?.
    - Prelude (mind submerged in night feeling), unspecified medium., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Sketch in pencil. [4] p.; 34 cm.
    - Preludio II (in memoriam Edgar Allan Poe), for orchestra., 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      Holograph in ink wirh corrections in pencil. Score (12 p.); 35 cm. Incomplete, last pages wanting?
    - Preludio e Fuga à 9 voci, [for orchestra?], 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
    - [Quartet, strings, no. 3] String quartet III., 2 (Box 11, Folder 147)
      Holograph signed, in ink. Score ([1] leaf.); 28 cm. Onionskin. Incomplete, last pages wanting?
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([3] p.); 35 cm. Unidentified sketch in ink on back.
    - [Quartet, strings, no. 5] String quartet V., 1 (Box 11, Folder 147)
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([1] leaf); 34 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings] Streichquartet., 2 (Box 11, Folder 147)
      Sketches in pencil. Scores (1 leaf, [4] p.); 32 cm.
    - [Quintet, 2 violins, 2 violas, violoncello & soprano] Another version: Quintet., 4 (Box 11, Folder 148-149)
      - Holograph signed, in ink. Score (23 p.); 34 cm. and parts [copyist's hand? pasted copies] 32 cm., 2 (Box 11, Folder 148-149)
      - Photocopy of score. 36 cm., 1 (Box 11, Folder 150)
    - So, [piano?], 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Sketch in pencil. [21 p.; 32 cm.
    - [Sonata, [piano?], no. 2] Sonata II., 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Sketch in pencil. 32 cm. Not Piano sonata no. 2 (1966)?
    - [Sonata, unspecified medium, no. 2] Sonata II?, 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Sketch in pencil with title in ink. 31 cm.
    - [Sonata, piano] Sonatina., 2 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Holograph in ink with corrections in pencil. 4 p.; 32 cm. Incomplete, last pages wanting?
      Another version: Sonatine.
    - [Sonata, unspecified medium] Sonata in F., 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] p.; 34 cm. Sketch of unidentified song on back.
    - [Songs, chamber orchestra acc., op. 2], 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Drei Gesänge mit kleine Orchester. Werk 2.
      Another version: Gesang für Sopran und kleine Orchester.
      Sketch signed, in ink. Score (2 p.); 36 cm. Sketch in ink for Streichquartett, Werk 5, on back.
      I. Sommerabend, words by Richard Debruel.
    - The specter dances, [for orchestra?], 2 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Sketches in pencil. Score (2, [1] p.); 34 cm.
    - [Stabat mater] Stabat mater, for [chorus (sopranos)?] and orchestra., 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Holograph in ink. Score ([2] p.); 34 cm. Incomplete, last pages wanting?
    - Studie nach Mozart, [piano?], 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Holograph in ink with corrections in pencil. [2] p.; 32 cm.
    - [Suite, string orchestra, no. 1] Suite I for strings., 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([1] leaf.); 35 cm.
    - [Symphony, no. 2, D minor] Sinfonia II., 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Sketch in pencil. Condensed score ([1] p.); 33 cm. Unidentified sketch on back.
      Another version: Symphony II in D minor.
      Sketches in pencil. Scores ([4 p., 2 leaves]); 35, 34 cm.
    - [Symphony, no. 2] Symphony 2 to the United Nations., 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
    - [Symphony, no. 3] Symphony III., 1 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Holograph in pencil. Score (23, [1] p.); 34 cm. Incomplete, 2nd page of movement II is wanting.
    - [Symphony, no. 3] Symphony III for soprano and strings., 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([1] leaf.); 34 cm.
    - [Symphony, string orchestra, no. 4] Symphony IV for string orchestra., 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
    - Trois sonnets de Rimbaud - chant et piano., 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      Sketches in pencil. Piano-vocal score (2 p.); 34 cm.
    - [Variations, string quartet?], 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      Holograph in ink with corrections in pencil. Score ([2] p.); 35 cm. Incomplete, last pages wanting?
    - Visione, for orchestra., 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      Parts. Holographs signed, in ink. 34 cm. Included are: oboe I, horn I-IV, trumpet I-II, trombone I-III, timpani, cymbals, bass drum, viola.
    - [Works, piano, no. 3], 1 (Box 11, Folder 152)
      Holograph in ink. [2] p.; 35 em.
      Loose pages of unidentified holographs of Loos's works.
      See typed letters signed from Jacques-Louis Monod (1982 Oct 29) laid in at end. Copies of music he identified are laid in folder 157.
  - Miscellaneous works, XIV.C
    - Loose pages of unidentified holographs of Loos's works. (Box 11, Folder 153-154, Box 12, Folder 155-157)
  - Index by medium, XIV.D
    This subseries is an index by medium of Loos's works. The indications "A" and "B" beside an entry indicate the subseries in which the main entry is found.
    - Orchestra, XIV.D.1
      - Aquarius 70 -- A, 1970; 9 (Box 10, Folder 140-141)
      - Ciacconna -- A, 1932; 1 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      - [Concerto, violin] -- A, 1965; 1 (Box 9, Folder 134)
      - [Divertimento, orchestra] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - Elegia -- A, 1931 Mar 9; 1 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - In my distress I called upon the Lord -- B, no date; 1 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - Lento -- B, no date; 9 (Box 10, Folder 144-145, Box 12, Folder 160, Box 4)
      - Missa spiritorum -- A, [1948]; 4 (Box 8, Folder 124-125, Box 12, Folder 159)
      - Musica atonale for orchestra -- A, 1929; 1 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      - Music for orchestra II -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Music for strings -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Musica per orchestra -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Mysterium -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - [Overture] -- A, 1932; 4 (Box 5, Folder 105)
      - [Overture] -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - Pastorale and perpetuum mobile -- A, 1941; 2 (Box 7, Folder 121-122)
      - Percepts -- A, 1969; 5 (Box 10, Folder 137-138)
      - Pezzo magico? -- B, no date; 1 (Box 11, Folder 146)
      - [Pieces, orchestra, op. 4] -- A, 1933 Oct 6; no date; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - [Pieces, orchestra] -- A, 1937-1938; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Pisces? -- A, 1970; 1 (Box 10, Folder 141)
      - Prayer for my wife -- A, 1936 Mar 3-11; 3 (Box 6, Folder 108)